<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dissertation on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/categories/dissertation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dissertation on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 18:09:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/categories/dissertation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>It’s Official. I’m Hitting Pause on My Ph.D. for a Year</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/its-official-im-hitting-pause-on-my-ph-d-for-a-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 18:09:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/its-official-im-hitting-pause-on-my-ph-d-for-a-year/</guid>
      <description>I received word yesterday that the Ph.D. Committee voted to approve my request for “Excused Program Leave” beginning in January 2021 and lasting until January 2022.
At the risk of sounding like Captain Obvious, 2020 has been a particularly difficult year.
Attempting to complete my “Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Bible” dissertation has taken a toll on my mental health as I ran into some major research and writing roadblocks right before and during the COVID pandemic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ph.D. Plan (Or the Lack Thereof)</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/the-phd-plan-or-the-lack-thereof/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 21:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/the-phd-plan-or-the-lack-thereof/</guid>
      <description>For months and months now, I’ve been praying for either (1) a breakthrough on my “Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Bible” dissertation or (2) a clear sign that I should quit the Ph.D. Unfortunately, after countless confusing dead ends in my endeavors to put Karl Barth and Dietrich Bonhoeffer into precise conversation with each other regarding specific passages of the Bible, I’ve now realized that such an approach is not going to work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Want a taste of what my dissertation is about? Read these two passages (Dissertation Dispatch, 2020-04-03)</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/want-a-taste-of-what-my-dissertation-is-about-read-these-two-passages-dissertation-dispatch-2020-04-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 13:38:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/want-a-taste-of-what-my-dissertation-is-about-read-these-two-passages-dissertation-dispatch-2020-04-03/</guid>
      <description>What does “religion” mean? Great question! I’m writing my dissertation on Barth, Bonhoeffer, the Bible, and “religion.” However, getting clear on just what Barth and Bonhoeffer meant by “religion” is a huge challenge. It’s what I devoted my entire writing sample to examining, and I plan to devote an entire chapter of my dissertation to the topic.
Neither Barth nor Bonhoeffer used the word “religion” in the way that we’re prone to use the word in everyday speech today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What did Barth and Bonhoeffer think of the Bible? (Dissertation Dispatch, 2020-03-30)</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/what-did-barth-and-bonhoeffer-think-of-the-bible-dissertation-dispatch-2020-03-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 14:53:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/what-did-barth-and-bonhoeffer-think-of-the-bible-dissertation-dispatch-2020-03-30/</guid>
      <description>I’m trying to parse out the relevance of Barth’s and Bonhoeffer’s engagement with Scripture for making sense of the “Barth-Bonhoeffer relationship.” Specifically, I’m trying to, at the very least, add some biblical content and context to the ongoing debate over the relationship between Barth’s and Bonhoeffer’s theological critiques of religion.
As I put it in the “elevator pitch” for my dissertation proposal:
In order to answer these questions (or at least move toward an answer), I’ve spent a considerable amount of time looking for specific biblical passages that (1) both Barth and Bonhoeffer discussed (2) at least thematically in relation to their theological critiques of religion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Bible: Back to the Beginning (Dissertation Dispatch, 2020-03-26)</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/barth-bonhoeffer-and-the-bible-back-to-the-beginning-dissertation-dispatch-2020-03-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 14:27:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/barth-bonhoeffer-and-the-bible-back-to-the-beginning-dissertation-dispatch-2020-03-26/</guid>
      <description>Perhaps it’s just the global COVID–19 pandemic, but I’ve been really discouraged about my dissertation lately.
My normal reading/writing workflow has ground to a halt because (1) we are temporarily without childcare and (2) my wife, a Family Nurse Practitioner is still working full-time from the office. That leaves me home alone with our 1.5-year-old during the week and, while she is a wonderful child, she’s not really jazzed about dad sitting quietly in a corner getting some reading and writing done during the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are the Beatitudes “Renunciations” (Verzichte)?</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/are-the-beatitudes-renunciations-verzichte/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 12:46:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/are-the-beatitudes-renunciations-verzichte/</guid>
      <description>In Discipleship (DBWE 4), Dietrich Bonhoeffer frames all of the Beatitudes in terms of Jesus’ disciples living in renunciation (Verzicht) and want (Mangel).
Interestingly, for Bonhoeffer, Jesus is only speaking to his disciples in the Beatitudes (he makes this argument on the basis of Luke 6:20ff.). And the disciples’ renunciation and want are caused by Jesus’s call to discipleship.
Bonhoeffer also writes:
Although Bonhoeffer is willing to frame all of the Beatitudes in terms of want and (especially) renunciation, he takes issue with August Tholuck’s distinction between some of the Beatitudes speaking of want “and others of the disciples’ intentional renunciation or special virtues” (DBWE 4:101; cf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are the Beatitudes “Good Works”? (Matt. 5:13–16)</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/are-the-beatitudes-good-works-matt-51316/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 19:13:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/are-the-beatitudes-good-works-matt-51316/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, I wrote just a bit about interpretive approaches to the Beatitudes in Matthew 5. I’m trying to get a better handle on how Barth and Bonhoeffer treat the Sermon on the Mount, and I’m starting with the Beatitudes.
However, it’s pretty challenging to situate Barth and Bonhoeffer in light of the “standard” approaches to both the Beatitudes and the Sermon on the Mount. A case in point: yesterday, I felt pretty confident that Bonhoeffer does not take the standard “entrance requirements” approach to the Beatitudes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpretive Approaches to the Beatitudes</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/interpretive-approaches-to-the-beatitudes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2019 19:48:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/interpretive-approaches-to-the-beatitudes/</guid>
      <description>As I said in my previous post, “Interpretive Approaches to the Sermon on the Mount,” I’m working on how Karl Barth and Dietrich Bonhoeffer read the Sermon on the Mount.
Of course, when interpreting the Sermon on the Mount, the best place to start is at the beginning! This means beginning with the Beatitudes in Matthew 5:1–12.
The Beatitudes (Matt. 5:1–12) Here’s Luke’s version of the Beatitudes (Luke 6:20–26) So, what should we make of the Beatitudes?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpretive Approaches to the Sermon on the Mount</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/interpretive-approaches-to-the-sermon-on-the-mount/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 22:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/interpretive-approaches-to-the-sermon-on-the-mount/</guid>
      <description>I’m working on how Karl Barth and Dietrich Bonhoeffer read the Sermon on the Mount.
In order to help situate my discussion of Barth’s and Bonhoeffer’s readings, I’m trying to get a better grasp of the various interpretive approaches to the Sermon on the Mount. So far, the most exhaustive Sermon on the Mount “interpretive taxonomy” that I’ve found has been from Grant Osborne’s Matthew (Zondervan Exegetical Commentary on the New Testament; Grand Rapids: Zondervan, 2010), 159.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No One Knows what “Positivism of Revelation” Means!</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/no-one-knows-what-positivism-of-revelation-means/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 02:54:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/no-one-knows-what-positivism-of-revelation-means/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to the Barth-Bonhoeffer relationship, there is perhaps no greater conundrum than the meaning of what Bonhoeffer called Barth’s “Offenbarungspositivismus” (“positivism of revelation” or “revelatory positivism”) in his Letters and Papers from Prison (DBWE 8).
Now, before we proceed, please note that Bonhoeffer meant something very particular by “religion” in his prison letters. For an overview of how Bonhoeffer and Barth differed on the meaning of “religion,” and what that means for how we interpret their theological critiques of religion, please see my essay: “To Be or Not To Be Religious: A Clarification of Karl Barth’s and Dietrich Bonhoeffer’s Divergence and Convergence Regarding Religion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I’m quite excited for these Oxford Handbooks!</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/im-quite-excited-for-these-oxford-handbooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 16:40:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/im-quite-excited-for-these-oxford-handbooks/</guid>
      <description>If you’ve not yet consulted the Oxford Handbook series, you should! The Oxford Handbook of Systematic Theology is especially useful!
I’m very excited because the Oxford Handbook of Dietrich Bonhoeffer and the Oxford Handbook of Karl Barth are both about to be released soon!
I just wish they weren’t so expensive!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barth Timeline: A Chronology of Karl Barth’s Life</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/barth-timeline-a-chronology-of-karl-barths-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 16:07:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/barth-timeline-a-chronology-of-karl-barths-life/</guid>
      <description>I really like the timelines of Bonhoeffer’s life that are available in The Cambridge Companion to Dietrich Bonhoeffer and in Bethge’s Dietrich Bonhoeffer: A Biography. (Those last two links are Amazon affiliate links.)
However, I’m having a much harder time finding comparable timelines for the life of Karl Barth. The information is all there, but there’s no comparable table/list of dates in either The Cambridge Companion to Karl Barth or Busch’s Karl Barth: His Life from Letters and Autobiographical Texts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bonhoeffer Timeline: A Chronology of Dietrich Bonhoeffer’s Life</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/bonhoeffer-timeline-a-brief-chronology-of-dietrich-bonhoeffers-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 15:21:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/bonhoeffer-timeline-a-brief-chronology-of-dietrich-bonhoeffers-life/</guid>
      <description>The Cambridge Companion to Dietrich Bonhoeffer SOURCE (Amazon affiliate link): John W. de Gruchy, ed., The Cambridge Companion to Dietrich Bonhoeffer (Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 1999), xxiv–xxvi.
1906, 4 February, Dietrich Bonhoeffer born in Breslau, Germany 1912 Family moves to Berlin, where Karl Bonhoeffer, Dietrich’s father, takes up a position at Berlin University 1913 Dietrich Bonhoeffer begins gymnasium studies 1916 Family moves to the suburb of Grunewald 1918 Walter Bonhoeffer, Dietrich’s brother, dies on the western front 1921 Dietrich and twin sister, Sabine, are confirmed 1923 Begins theological studies at Tübingen 1924 Continues theological studies at Berlin; travels to Rome and north Africa with elder brother Klaus 1927 Qualifies for licentiate with his doctoral dissertation, Sanctorum Communio (DBWE 1) 1928 Curate in Barcelona 1929 Summer lectures in systematic theology, Berlin; assistant pastor in Berlin 1930 Completes second dissertation, later published as Act and Being (DBWE 2); Sloane Fellow at Union Theological Seminary, New York (1930-1) 1931 July: first meeting with Karl Barth August: lecturer in theological faculty, Berlin September: appointed Youth Secretary of World Alliance for Promoting International Friendship through the Churches Conference, Cambridge October: chaplain at Technical College, Berlin November: takes confirmation class in Berlin-Wedding 1932 Winter lecture course on ‘Creation and Sin’ (later published as Creation and Fall (DBWE 3))</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dissertation Dispatch: 2019-11-11</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/dissertation-dispatch-2019-11-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 18:58:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/dissertation-dispatch-2019-11-11/</guid>
      <description>I’m narrowing my focus to Genesis 1–3 and the Sermon on the Mount. Originally, my dissertation proposal cast a very wide net. I was going to have the following chapters:
Introduction (5,000 words) Chapter 1: Creation and Fall (Genesis 1–3) (16,000 words) Chapter 2: The Prophets (16,000 words) Chapter 3: The Gospels (16,000 words) Chapter 4: The Epistle to the Romans (16,000 words) Chapter 5: Completing the Biblical Critique of Religion (16,000 words) Summary and Conclusion (5,000 words) However, after doing survey work, and spending most of the previous academic year working on Barth and Bonhoeffer’s reading of Genesis 1–3, I’ve decided to narrow my focus down to Genesis 1–3 and the Sermon on the Mount.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Following Christ as a Hermeneutical Problem?</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/following-christ-as-a-hermeneutical-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 13:58:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/following-christ-as-a-hermeneutical-problem/</guid>
      <description>I’m trying to puzzle out the meaning of the following paragraph from Bonhoeffer’s Discipleship (DBWE 4).
Dietrich Bonhoeffer, Discipleship, ed. Martin Kuske et al., trans. Barbara Green and Reinhard Krauss, vol. 4, Dietrich Bonhoeffer Works (Minneapolis, MN: Fortress Press, 2003), 82.
Here, Bonhoeffer appears to be contrasting the “simple obedience” required by a “costly grace” approach with a “paradoxical obedience” required by a “cheap grace” approach. The latter approach makes “a general doctrine of grace,” and not “the living Christ himself,” the “principle of scripture” (Schriftprinzip).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dissertation Dispatch: 2019-08-09</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/dissertation-dispatch-2019-08-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 15:21:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/dissertation-dispatch-2019-08-09/</guid>
      <description>This summer, I’ve spent most of my reading/writing time working on a paper on Barth’s Römerbrief reading of Romans 10. This paper is for the 2019 Barth Graduate Student Colloquium, and it has taken way longer than I originally anticipated.
Will I get to use this paper in my dissertation? I’m not sure.
At first, I got excited, because, in my work on Genesis 1–3 last school year, I discovered some differences in how Barth and Bonhoeffer handled Genesis 1–3 vis-a-vis the subsequent history of Israel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Guilt of Karl Barth: Strengths and Weaknesses of Barth’s Römerbrief Reading of Romans 9:30–10:21</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/the-guilt-of-karl-barth-strengths-and-weaknesses-of-barths-romerbrief-reading-of-romans-9301021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 14:38:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/the-guilt-of-karl-barth-strengths-and-weaknesses-of-barths-romerbrief-reading-of-romans-9301021/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: Here is the paper that I gave at the 2019 Karl Barth Graduate Student Colloquium at the Center for Barth Studies at Princeton Theological Seminary.
INTRODUCTION: “GENTILES” = “WORLD” IS WORSE THAN “ISRAEL” = “CHURCH” On at least one level, Karl Barth’s Römerbrief reading of Romans 9–11 is supersessionist. In general, especially in the second edition, when Paul refers to “Israel” in Romans 9–11, Barth refers to the “Church.”[1] He replaces Israel with the Church.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I think Karl Barth missed the (pastoral) point of Romans</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/i-think-karl-barth-missed-the-pastoral-point-of-romans/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 15:44:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/i-think-karl-barth-missed-the-pastoral-point-of-romans/</guid>
      <description>I’m scheduled to give a paper on Karl Barth’s reading of Romans 9:30–10:21 in Der Römerbrief at the 2019 Barth Graduate Student Colloquium at Princeton in August.
Now, of course, it’s a pleasure and a privilege to give a paper at the colloquium. However, in hindsight, I don’t know why I thought giving a paper on chapter 10 of Barth’s Römerbrief was a good idea!
Granted, I don’t have to solve all of the exegetical issues (of which there are many) in Romans 9:30–10:21.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dissertation Dispatch: 2019-07-05</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/dissertation-dispatch-2019-07-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 21:09:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/dissertation-dispatch-2019-07-05/</guid>
      <description>I got my dissertation proposal approved in the Spring of 2018. Working title: “Scriptural but Not Religious: Karl Barth, Dietrich Bonhoeffer, and a Biblical Critique of Religion.”
Barth + Bonhoeffer + Bible + Religion. “Barth, Bonhoeffer, and Bible” is the gap/niche. But that would be too much to tackle comprehensively in a dissertation. So “religion” is designed to be the delimiter—specifically, Barth’s and Bonhoeffer’s theological critiques of religion.
Dissertation-wise, I didn’t make as much progress as I would’ve liked to during the 2018–19 school year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Desperate Times, Desperate Measures: Writing My Dissertation vs. Funding Abortion</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/desperate-times-desperate-measures-writing-my-dissertation-vs-funding-abortion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 13:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/desperate-times-desperate-measures-writing-my-dissertation-vs-funding-abortion/</guid>
      <description>I’m two years in to my PhD program, and I need to finish writing this dissertation soon, or it’s going to be the death of me!
Don’t get me wrong. I love Wheaton’s program. My supervisor and second reader are fantastic. And I think that this Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Bible project is worthwhile.
But I’ve got a wife, a kid, a commitment to the Church, and I need to move on with my life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dietrich Bonhoeffer’s Sermons and Meditations</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/dietrich-bonhoeffers-sermons-and-meditations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 15:04:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/dietrich-bonhoeffers-sermons-and-meditations/</guid>
      <description>SOURCE: Dietrich Bonhoeffer, Indexes and Supplementary Materials, ed. Victoria J. Barnett et al., vol. 17, Dietrich Bonhoeffer Works (Minneapolis, MN: Fortress Press, 2014), 154–158.
Sermons and Meditations Address on Jeremiah 27–28—(DBWE vol. )9
Address on John 19—9
Address on Luke 12:35ff.—9
Address on Matthew 21:28–31—9
Address on the Decalogue—9
Address on the First Commandment—9
Baptismal Homily on Joshua 24:15—13
Baptism Sermon on 1 John 4:16—11
Baptism Sermon on Ephesians 5:14—11</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tree of Religion: Karl Barth and Dietrich Bonhoeffer on the Tree of Knowledge in Genesis 2:4–3:24</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/the-tree-of-religion-karl-barth-and-dietrich-bonhoeffer-on-the-tree-of-knowledge-in-genesis-24-324/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 15:51:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/the-tree-of-religion-karl-barth-and-dietrich-bonhoeffer-on-the-tree-of-knowledge-in-genesis-24-324/</guid>
      <description>(Here’s a PDF of this paper: STEELE_The Tree of Religion Barth and Bonhoeffer on the Tree of Knowledge.)
Introduction The precise meaning of the “tree of the knowledge of good and evil” (=TK) has long vexed interpreters of Genesis 2:4–3:24.1 While the “tree of life” (=TL) is mentioned and alluded to throughout the Bible, the TK is explicitly mentioned by its full name just twice (Gen. 2:9, 17).[2] Nevertheless, because of the significant role that the TK plays in the narrative, both Dietrich Bonhoeffer and Karl Barth highlight the TK in their theological interpretations of Genesis 1–3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theology is exegesis: John Webster on what we can learn from Barth and Bonhoeffer</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/theology-is-exegesis-john-webster-on-what-we-can-learn-from-barth-and-bonhoeffer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 16:12:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/theology-is-exegesis-john-webster-on-what-we-can-learn-from-barth-and-bonhoeffer/</guid>
      <description>John Webster’s essay, “Reading the Bible: The Example of Barth and Bonhoeffer” (pages 87–110 in Word and Church: Essays in Christian Dogmatics [Edinburgh; New York: T&amp;amp;T Clark, 2001]) is, in large part, the inspiration for my doctoral dissertation.
I’d like to share the three reflections/lessons Webster draws from the biblical work of Barth and Bonhoeffer.
Wrapping up his essay, Webster claims that
Neither Bonhoeffer nor Barth were wissenschaftlich theologians; both were practical or pastoral theologians of the church of Jesus Christ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barth, the Bible, and “What we ought to do”</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/barth-the-bible-and-what-we-ought-to-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 17:46:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/barth-the-bible-and-what-we-ought-to-do/</guid>
      <description>Came across this Barth quote in Church Dogmatics II/2 this morning. I really like it, because it’s a good reminder that Barth valued the Bible. His distinction between the Bible as witness to the Word of God and Jesus Christ as the Word of God did not cause him to abandon the Scriptural witness.
It is as well to remind ourselves, at the conclusion of this analysis, that the question: What ought we to do?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Karl Barth’s Gesamtausgabe (“Complete/Collected Edition”): A List of Works</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/karl-barths-gesamtausgabe-complete-collected-edition-a-list-of-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 17:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/karl-barths-gesamtausgabe-complete-collected-edition-a-list-of-works/</guid>
      <description>Note that, as of 2019-01-26, 54 volumes of the Gesamtausgabe have been published.
Unfortunately, only the first 45 of these are available in the Digital Karl Barth Library.
*I’ve marked volumes unavailable in the DKBL with an asterisk.
According to the publisher, TVZ:
Seit 1971 sind im Theologischen Verlag Zürich mehr als 50 Bände der Karl Barth-Gesamtausgabe erschienen. In ihr werden Barths Texte kritisch ediert und so präsentiert, dass sie für die wissenschaftliche Beschäftigung, aber auch für einen grösseren Interessentenkreis lesbar und zugänglich werden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A List of Karl Barth’s Sermons</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/a-list-of-karl-barths-sermons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 16:57:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/a-list-of-karl-barths-sermons/</guid>
      <description>To make this list, I’ve used the data available in the Digital Karl Barth Library. I’ve just taken the tables of contents in the sermon volumes of Barth’s collected works and put them all in one place.
The only way to display the dates correctly in Markdown is to write these up as code blocks, as I’ve done below.
Predigten 1913 (GA I.8) 1. und 5. Januar (Neujahr): Prediger 1,9 12.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barth and Bonhoeffer on Religion’s False God(s)</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/barth-and-bonhoeffer-on-religions-false-gods/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 19:08:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/barth-and-bonhoeffer-on-religions-false-gods/</guid>
      <description>In The Epistle to the Romans, Barth writes the following concerning the false image of God at the heart of religion:
What men on this side resurrection name ‘God’ is most characteristically not God. Their ‘God’ does not redeem his creation, but allows free course to the unrighteousness of men; does not declare himself to be God, but is the complete affirmation of the course of the world and of men as it is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Karl Barth’s Reversal on the “Knowledge of Good and Evil”</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/karl-barths-reversal-on-the-knowledge-of-good-and-evil/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 19:07:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/karl-barths-reversal-on-the-knowledge-of-good-and-evil/</guid>
      <description>I argue that, although Barth’s interpretation of the Genesis passages changed between The Epistle to the Romans and the Church Dogmatics, his mature readings of Genesis 2–3 still support his overall theological critique of religion as idolatry, the self-justifying positing of false gods.
Specifically, in Romans (240–57, esp. 246–51), Barth interpreted “the knowledge of good and evil” as the divine secret that humans are merely humans.
The prohibition of eating from the tree of knowledge thereby concealed the creator/creature distinction and was meant to enable a direct relationship between God and humans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I wish these 2 Barth (and Bonhoeffer) books would come out sooner!</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/i-wish-these-2-barth-and-bonhoeffer-books-would-come-out-sooner/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 22:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/i-wish-these-2-barth-and-bonhoeffer-books-would-come-out-sooner/</guid>
      <description>(Note: Read more about my work on Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Bible here.)
I’m really looking forward to reading these two Barth (and Bonhoeffer) books coming out from Baker in 2019:
Freedom under the Word: Karl Barth’s Theological Exegesis. Edited by Ben Rhodes and Martin Westerholm. Karl Barth and Dietrich Bonhoeffer: Theologians for a Post-Christian World. By Wolf Krötke. Translated by John P. Burgess. Freedom under the Word (May 2019) According to Baker:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bonhoeffer’s “Definition” of “Religion” in Prison: 15 Facets/Aspects</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/bonhoeffers-definition-of-religion-in-prison-15-facets-aspects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 14:59:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/bonhoeffers-definition-of-religion-in-prison-15-facets-aspects/</guid>
      <description>Based upon my own reading of Bonhoeffer’s Letters and Papers from Prison [DBWE 8], here is my attempt at a summary list of the facets/aspects of Bonhoeffer’s view of “religion” in prison.
Religion emphasizes inwardness. [DBWE 8:362, 364, 455–57] Religion emphasizes conscience. [DBWE 8:362] Religion is a temporary phenomenon. [DBWE 8:362, 364] Religion is manipulative and exploitative. [DBWE 8:363, 366, 426–27, 450, 455–57] Religion ignores human strength/knowledge/autonomy and instead focuses on human weakness, ignorance, and boundaries/limits/limitations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Karl Barth Software Drama Continues: Inaccurate Page Numbers in Logos</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/my-karl-barth-software-drama-continues-inaccurate-page-numbers-in-logos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 16:12:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/my-karl-barth-software-drama-continues-inaccurate-page-numbers-in-logos/</guid>
      <description>Previously, I wrote about how the Scripture search tool in the Digital Karl Barth Library was broken. Thankfully, it appears to have been fixed (although it still has issues). This means I can search Barth’s “Collected Edition” (Gesamtausgabe) if needed.
However, I’m now having some issues with the copy of Barth’s Church Dogmatics I purchased via Logos Bible Software.
Before I complain, let me first say how grateful I am that Logos is MUCH more user-friendly than the Digital Karl Barth Library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UPDATE: You can now search for Bible citations in the Digital Karl Barth Library again</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/update-you-can-now-search-for-bible-citations-in-the-digital-karl-barth-library-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:45:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/update-you-can-now-search-for-bible-citations-in-the-digital-karl-barth-library-again/</guid>
      <description>I recently wrote about a problem I found in Alexander Street Press’ Digital Karl Barth Library: the Scripture citation search function no longer worked!
I’m happy to report that, though the DKBL is still far from user-friendly, the Bible search works again!
Now we just need some angel investors and programmers to produce a user-friendly version of the Digital Karl Barth Library! 🙂 Any takers?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s gone wrong with the Digital Karl Barth Library?</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/whats-gone-wrong-with-the-digital-karl-barth-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 15:29:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/whats-gone-wrong-with-the-digital-karl-barth-library/</guid>
      <description>As I slowly make progress on my dissertation (“Scriptural but Not Religious: Karl Barth, Dietrich Bonhoeffer, and a Biblical Critique of Religion”), I’m longing for the day when:
Karl Barth’s Gesamtausgabe (Collected Edition) is finished. They are translated into a critical English edition. They are available within the same database/framework as Dietrich Bonhoeffer’s Works in English and German (DBWE and DBW). In the meantime, the Digital Karl Barth Library, provided by Alexander Street Press is the best resource out there for searching the text of Barth’s works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here’s the Template I Use to Take Notes on Books I Read</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/heres-the-template-i-use-to-take-notes-on-books-i-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 19:41:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/heres-the-template-i-use-to-take-notes-on-books-i-read/</guid>
      <description>Developed from How to Read a Book, by Mortimer J. Adler.
BIBLIOGRAPHIC DATA: Author(s):
Editor(s):
Translator(s):
Title and subtitle:
Title and subtitle of any larger work that contains the source:
Pages:
Volume:
Issue:
Edition:
URL and date accessed:
Publisher:
Place:
Date:
INTERPRETATION: Kind of Book (Practical or theoretical?):
Subject Matter:
Problems Attempted to Solve:
Summary (What is the book about as a whole?):
Outline of Source:
Key Terms:
Key Propositions/Arguments (What is being said in detail, and how?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here’s the Elevator Pitch for my Dissertation Proposal: “Scriptural, but Not Religious”</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/heres-the-elevator-pitch-for-my-dissertation-proposal-scriptural-but-not-religious/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 21:30:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/heres-the-elevator-pitch-for-my-dissertation-proposal-scriptural-but-not-religious/</guid>
      <description>Tomorrow, I defend the proposal for my dissertation. For now, the dissertation is tentatively titled: “Scriptural, but Not Religious: Karl Barth, Dietrich Bonhoeffer, and a Biblical Critique of Religion.”
Here’s the “elevator pitch” for the dissertation. Feedback appreciated.
Scriptural, but Not Religious: Barth, Bonhoeffer, and a Biblical Critique of Religion My project traces its origins to a single classroom discussion question in the Spring of 2015. The question was this: “In what ways is Bonhoeffer’s understanding of religion similar to, and different from, that of Barth?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Be or Not To Be Religious: A Clarification of Karl Barth’s and Dietrich Bonhoeffer’s Divergence and Convergence Regarding Religion</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/to-be-or-not-to-be-religious-a-clarification-of-karl-barths-and-dietrich-bonhoeffers-divergence-and-convergence-regarding-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 18:15:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/to-be-or-not-to-be-religious-a-clarification-of-karl-barths-and-dietrich-bonhoeffers-divergence-and-convergence-regarding-religion/</guid>
      <description>(Note: Read more about my work on Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Bible here.)
Christian theologians Karl Barth (1886-1968) and Dietrich Bonhoeffer (1906-1945) inherited a particular understanding of religion. In the broadly post-Kantian milieu, nineteenth-century thinkers such as Friedrich Schleiermacher, Albrecht Ritschl, and Adolf von Harnack defined religion essentially, anthropologically, and subjectively. That is, religion has a particular essence, and is in some manner inalienable from our humanity. The emphasis of this conception is on the experience of the religious subject, instead of the knowledge of religion’s object (let alone its reality).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30 Works on Karl Barth &amp; Dietrich Bonhoeffer. Are There Others?</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/works-on-barth-and-bonhoeffer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 20:03:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/works-on-barth-and-bonhoeffer/</guid>
      <description>ABROMEIT, Hans-Jürgen. Das Geheimnis Christi: Dietrich Bonhoeffers erfahrungsbezogene Christologie. Neukirchener Beiträge zur systemaschen Theologie 8. Neukirchen-Vluyn: Neukirchener Verlag, 1991. BEINTKER, Michael. “Kontingenz und Gegenständlichkeit: Zu Bonhoeffers Barth-Kritik in ‘Akt und Sein.’” In Krisis und Gnade: Gesammelte Studien zu Karl Barth, edited by Stefan Holtmann and Peter Zocher, 29–54. Tübingen: Mohr Siebeck, 2013. BENKTSON, Benkt-Erik. Christus Und Die Religion: Der Religionsbegriff Bei Barth, Bonhoeffer Und Tillich. Arbeiten Zur Theologie, II/9. Stuttgart: Calwer, 1967.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barth, Bonhoeffer, &amp; The Theological Critique of Religion: My Reading List This Fall</title>
      <link>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/barth-bonhoeffer-the-theological-critique-of-religion-my-reading-list-this-fall/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 20:30:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsteelepfpt.github.io/barth-bonhoeffer-the-theological-critique-of-religion-my-reading-list-this-fall/</guid>
      <description>(Note: Read more about my work on Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Bible here.)
This semester — my final one at Beeson Divinity School — I’m doing a directed study with Piotr Malysz on the topic of “Religion” in Karl Barth and Dietrich Bonhoeffer.
The impetus for this study was a discussion question in Dr. Malysz’s Spring 2015 20th Century History and Doctrine course. On March 24, our third class period on Dietrich Bonhoeffer, our second question for discussion read as follows:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
