<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sermon on the Mount on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/sermon-on-the-mount/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sermon on the Mount on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 12:46:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/sermon-on-the-mount/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Are the Beatitudes “Renunciations” (Verzichte)?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/are-the-beatitudes-renunciations-verzichte/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 12:46:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/are-the-beatitudes-renunciations-verzichte/</guid>
      <description>In Discipleship (DBWE 4), Dietrich Bonhoeffer frames all of the Beatitudes in terms of Jesus’ disciples living in renunciation (Verzicht) and want (Mangel).
Interestingly, for Bonhoeffer, Jesus is only speaking to his disciples in the Beatitudes (he makes this argument on the basis of Luke 6:20ff.). And the disciples’ renunciation and want are caused by Jesus’s call to discipleship.
Bonhoeffer also writes:
Although Bonhoeffer is willing to frame all of the Beatitudes in terms of want and (especially) renunciation, he takes issue with August Tholuck’s distinction between some of the Beatitudes speaking of want “and others of the disciples’ intentional renunciation or special virtues” (DBWE 4:101; cf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpretive Approaches to the Beatitudes</title>
      <link>http://example.org/interpretive-approaches-to-the-beatitudes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2019 19:48:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/interpretive-approaches-to-the-beatitudes/</guid>
      <description>As I said in my previous post, “Interpretive Approaches to the Sermon on the Mount,” I’m working on how Karl Barth and Dietrich Bonhoeffer read the Sermon on the Mount.
Of course, when interpreting the Sermon on the Mount, the best place to start is at the beginning! This means beginning with the Beatitudes in Matthew 5:1–12.
The Beatitudes (Matt. 5:1–12) Here’s Luke’s version of the Beatitudes (Luke 6:20–26) So, what should we make of the Beatitudes?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpretive Approaches to the Sermon on the Mount</title>
      <link>http://example.org/interpretive-approaches-to-the-sermon-on-the-mount/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 22:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/interpretive-approaches-to-the-sermon-on-the-mount/</guid>
      <description>I’m working on how Karl Barth and Dietrich Bonhoeffer read the Sermon on the Mount.
In order to help situate my discussion of Barth’s and Bonhoeffer’s readings, I’m trying to get a better grasp of the various interpretive approaches to the Sermon on the Mount. So far, the most exhaustive Sermon on the Mount “interpretive taxonomy” that I’ve found has been from Grant Osborne’s Matthew (Zondervan Exegetical Commentary on the New Testament; Grand Rapids: Zondervan, 2010), 159.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
