<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Uncategorized on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://example.org/categories/uncategorized/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Uncategorized on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 20:10:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/categories/uncategorized/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Questions Worth Asking (Self-Elicitation Questions)</title>
      <link>http://example.org/questions-worth-asking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 20:10:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/questions-worth-asking/</guid>
      <description>Five-Minute Journal Questions Morning I am grateful for… What would make today great? Daily affirmations: I am… Evening What are 3 amazing things that happened today? How could I have made today even better? Morning Questions (5 minutes) What’s one thing I’m grateful for? What’s one thing I’m excited about? What’s one virtue I want to exhibit? What’s one thing I’m avoiding? What’s the one thing I need to do? Evening Questions (5 minutes) What were my biggest wins of the day?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentor Me! 11 Questions I’d Like You to Answer</title>
      <link>http://example.org/mentor-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 20:24:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/mentor-me/</guid>
      <description>Say what you will about Tim Ferriss, I’ve always really enjoyed the questions that he asks himself and others.
I also really enjoy LEARNING as much as I can from other people. And so, with that in mind, I’d like to “open source” my search for mentors and invite you, dear reader, to answer at least one of the questions below.
Please comment your answers below this post (that way others can benefit from your knowledge as well!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Haven’t You Torn The Sky Open Yet?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/why-havent-you-torn-the-sky-open-yet-sermon-first-sunday-of-advent-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:22:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/why-havent-you-torn-the-sky-open-yet-sermon-first-sunday-of-advent-2020/</guid>
      <description>Sermon preached on Saturday, November 28, 2020 (First Sunday of Advent) via Zoom at Church of the Savior in Wheaton, IL.
If there are two things I hate, they are waiting and staying awake. I hate waiting.
Ask anyone who knows me. I am absolutely horrible when it comes to delayed gratification. I’ve been known to open new boxes of cereal on the way home from the store.
And I hate staying awake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We switched Anglican Compass over from HostGator Shared to Bluehost VPS Hosting</title>
      <link>http://example.org/we-switched-anglican-compass-over-from-hostgator-shared-to-bluehost-vps-hosting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 15:28:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/we-switched-anglican-compass-over-from-hostgator-shared-to-bluehost-vps-hosting/</guid>
      <description>As of this morning, it looks like everything for Anglican Compass has been successfully moved over from our HostGator shared hosting to Bluehost VPS hosting.
I’m hoping that this new arrangement works well for us! Although, to be honest, it’s still an open question in my mind whether or not managed WordPress hosting with WPEngine would be a better fit. I just can’t quite tell whether or not it would be worth the extra cost, given our current traffic and budget.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“They laughed when I became an Anglican, but when I started to pray…” 27 Anglican Headline Ideas</title>
      <link>http://example.org/they-laughed-when-i-became-an-anglican-but-when-i-started-to-pray-27-anglican-headline-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 14:06:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/they-laughed-when-i-became-an-anglican-but-when-i-started-to-pray-27-anglican-headline-ideas/</guid>
      <description>I’m reading my way through the new (4th) edition of Robert Bly’s classic The Copywriter’s Handbook. On pages 33–36, Bly offers “38 Model Headlines for Your ‘Swipe File.&amp;rsquo;” Here are some headlines ideas that came to mind, all geared to an Anglican context (due to my work at AnglicanCompass.com).
Why are Anglicans so angry? How do I use the Book of Common Prayer? How can I become an Anglican? What do Anglicans believe?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Sermon on the Mount (Dissertation Dispatch 2020-02-04)</title>
      <link>http://example.org/barth-bonhoeffer-and-the-sermon-on-the-mount-dissertation-dispatch-2020-02-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 18:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/barth-bonhoeffer-and-the-sermon-on-the-mount-dissertation-dispatch-2020-02-04/</guid>
      <description>I’m still very much in the weeds, taking a closer look at how Bonhoeffer and Barth read the Sermon on the Mount.
Given the importance of the Sermon on Mount for Bonhoeffer’s life and work, I’m persuaded that there’s something important to be found here—something that will hopefully shed some light on the Barth-Bonhoeffer relationship re:their theological critiques of religion.
Additionally, there are at least two other tidbits that have me interested in how Barth and Bonhoeffer read the Sermon on the Mount.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quit claiming that we mutualists (egalitarians) don’t take the Bible or tradition seriously.</title>
      <link>http://example.org/quit-claiming-that-we-mutualists-egalitarians-dont-take-the-bible-or-tradition-seriously/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 16:54:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/quit-claiming-that-we-mutualists-egalitarians-dont-take-the-bible-or-tradition-seriously/</guid>
      <description>In the ongoing debate about women’s ordination (in the Anglican realm and beyond), I keep hearing oversimplified claims from hierarchicalists (or “complementarians,” but that’s not the most helpful term in this debate) that they have the entirety of the Bible and Church tradition on their side.
Therefore, we mutualists (or “egalitarians,” but that’s not the most helpful term in this debate), it is argued, have arrived at our positions for various reasons—perhaps capitulation to liberal cultural trends and hermeneutical methods—but not because we’ve read Scripture or studied the history of the Church very carefully.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Deacon’s Last Day</title>
      <link>http://example.org/a-deacons-last-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 02:35:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/a-deacons-last-day/</guid>
      <description>BCP 2019, 650.
I’m getting ordained to the priesthood tomorrow, and I’m both humbled and honored to serve Christ’s Church in this way.
Do I feel inherently worthy to be a presbyter? No.
Me, a 28-year-old, an elder?
But I do feel called.
I feel called to “spend and be spent for the sake of the Gospel.”
I feel called to preach the Word of God and administer the Sacraments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here’s what I’m committing myself to as a priest.</title>
      <link>http://example.org/heres-what-im-committing-myself-to-as-a-priest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 19:57:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/heres-what-im-committing-myself-to-as-a-priest/</guid>
      <description>I’m getting ordained to the priesthood this Saturday, November 02. For public/posterity’s sake, I wanted to post some of the main parts of the ordination liturgy (from the ACNA’s 2019 Book of Common Prayer).
The Presentation The Bishop and People sit. The Presenters, standing before the Bishop, present the Ordinand, saying
Reverend Father in God, we present N.N. to be admitted to the Order of Priests.
Bishop: Has he been selected in accordance with the Canons of this Church?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Prayer for Relatives and Friends</title>
      <link>http://example.org/a-prayer-for-relatives-and-friends/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 19:36:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/a-prayer-for-relatives-and-friends/</guid>
      <description>The ACNA Book of Common Prayer 2019, pp. 76–77.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Why You Never See Your Friends Anymore” (The Atlantic)</title>
      <link>http://example.org/why-you-never-see-your-friends-anymore-the-atlantic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 16:38:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/why-you-never-see-your-friends-anymore-the-atlantic/</guid>
      <description>Judith Shulevitz offers up a (depressing) eye-opening analysis of our overbusy lives. There is another way! But community and Sabbath both require sacrifice.
“Why You Never See Your Friends Anymore” (The Atlantic)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are the most important theological terms that every Christian should know?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/what-are-the-most-important-theological-terms-that-every-christian-should-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 14:14:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/what-are-the-most-important-theological-terms-that-every-christian-should-know/</guid>
      <description>Which theological terms would make your shortlist?
Here’s the list of terms found in “Jargon-Busting: A Glossary of Theological Terms,” at the back of Alister E. McGrath’s excellent Christian Theology: An Introduction (25th Anniversary Edition).
adoptionism aggiornamento Alexandrian School allegory Anabaptism analogy of being (analogia entis) analogy of faith (analogia fidei) anthropomorphism Antiochene School anti-Pelagian writings apocalyptic apologetics apophatic apostolic era appropriation Arianism atonement Barthian beatific vision Beatitudes Calvinism Cappadocian fathers Cartesianism catechism catharsis catholic Chalcedonian definition charisma, charismatic Charismatic movement Christology circumincessio conciliarism confession consubstantial consubstantiation contemplation creed Deism dialectical theology Docetism Donatism doxology Ebionitism ecclesiology Enlightenment eschatology Eucharist evangelical exegesis exemplarism fathers fideism filioque Five Ways fourth gospel fundamentalism hermeneutics hesychasm historical Jesus historico-critical method history of religions school homoousios humanism hypostatic union icons ideology incarnation justification by faith, doctrine of kenoticism kerygma liberal Protestantism liberation theology liturgy logos Lutheranism Manicheism modalism monophysitism neo-orthodoxy ontological argument orthodoxy parousia patripassianism patristic Pelagianism perichoresis Pietism postliberalism postmodernism praxis Protestantism Quadriga radical Reformation Reformed Sabellianism sacrament schism scholasticism Scripture principle Socinianism soteriology synoptic gospels synoptic problem theodicy theopaschitism theotokos Thomism transubstantiation Trinity two natures, doctrine of typology Vulgate Zwinglianism </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here are all of William Witt’s essays on Women’s ordination, in a single PDF (with bookmarks!)</title>
      <link>http://example.org/here-are-all-of-william-witts-essays-on-womens-ordination-in-a-single-pdf-with-bookmarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 15:28:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/here-are-all-of-william-witts-essays-on-womens-ordination-in-a-single-pdf-with-bookmarks/</guid>
      <description>Over on his blog, “Non Sermoni Res,” Dr. William Witt has written several excellent essays on the topic of women’s ordination.
Here’s the guide that Witt put together in order to orient readers to his essays.
What I’ve done is to combine the blog posts into a single PDF, with bookmarks. Here it is:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Outline of Karl Barth’s Church Dogmatics</title>
      <link>http://example.org/an-outline-of-karl-barths-church-dogmatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 15:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/an-outline-of-karl-barths-church-dogmatics/</guid>
      <description>If you’re trying to grasp the contours and contents of Karl Barth’s massive Church Dogmatics, it helps to have an outline! Here’s a helpful PDF version, with subheadings included, from Princeton’s Center for Barth Studies.
Below is a version that I’ve created from my Logos edition of Church Dogmatics. It’s the version found in the Index (CD V/1, 1–13).
VOLUME I INTRODUCTION §1 THE TASK OF DOGMATICS As a theological discipline dogmatics is the scientific self-examination of the Christian Church with respect to the content of its distinctive talk about God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Bible</title>
      <link>http://example.org/barth-bonhoeffer-and-the-bible/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 16:57:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/barth-bonhoeffer-and-the-bible/</guid>
      <description>John Webster’s Idea Like so many others, I desperately wish that John Webster were still alive.
After all, my dissertation topic owes much to his essay: “Reading the Bible: The Example of Barth and Bonhoeffer.”
The essay (previously published as ‘“In the Shadow of Biblical Work:” Barth and Bonhoeffer on Reading the Bible,’and then published in Word and Church: Essays in Christian Dogmatics) begins:
Here’s Webster’s suggestion for making sense of the Barth-Bonhoeffer relationship:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Only the Suffering God Can Help</title>
      <link>http://example.org/only-the-suffering-god-can-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:17:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/only-the-suffering-god-can-help/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn more about Rublev’s Trinity icon [video]</title>
      <link>http://example.org/learn-more-about-rublevs-trinity-icon-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 17:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/learn-more-about-rublevs-trinity-icon-video/</guid>
      <description>I’ve always wanted to learn more about Andrei Rublev’s famous icon of the Trinity. If you’re also curious, check out this video.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>http://example.org/41482-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 17:56:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/41482-2/</guid>
      <description>Black Friday! Capitalism! Death! Listen to this episode of Stuff You Should Know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>http://example.org/41480-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 17:14:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/41480-2/</guid>
      <description>Go Blue!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>http://example.org/41477-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 15:10:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/41477-2/</guid>
      <description>The St Andrews Encyclopaedia of Theology sounds like it will be a marvelous resource! Think the Stanford Encyclopedia of Philosophy, but for theology!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>http://example.org/41475-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 19:31:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/41475-2/</guid>
      <description>This is the best Advent/Christmas album I’ve ever listened to. The Oh Hellos Family Christmas Album</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>http://example.org/41473-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 15:45:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/41473-2/</guid>
      <description>If the “arc of history” bends toward anything other than randomness and destruction, it does so due to the grace of the Triune God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>http://example.org/41471-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 11:50:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/41471-2/</guid>
      <description>Interesting to compare the high holy day of Black Friday to the Christian liturgy. “Take and eat!” might sound similar to “consume!,” but they end up meaning very different things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>http://example.org/41431-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 14:30:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/41431-2/</guid>
      <description>This is a status test.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
